Marco Cencig

Web/Game Developer , CNC Programmer , Control Quality Officer

Contact

Address

56022, Villa Campanile Italia

+393483754620

E-mail

Marcocencig97@gmail.com

www

https://www.linkedin.com /in/marco-cencig-a81b36201/

https://bold.pro/my/marcocencig/321r

Skills

CNC lathe programming Tool path design **Javascript** CSS HTML5 React C# Game Mechanics Design Level Design Product Inspection **ChatGPT**

Software

SolidWorks Intermediate AutoCAD Intermediate Unity Upper intermediate GitHub Upper intermediate Visual Studio Code Upper intermediate

Languages

8 years of experience at Toscotec S.P.A. in CNC programming and quality control. 2 year of experience in web development with strong skills in HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, React.

4 years of experience in Unity and C#, applied in the development of the game Shattered Heaven, improving production efficiency and gameplay quality. Versatile CNC

Work History

2021-09 -2023-06

Game Developer

Leonardo Interactive, Remote

- Worked as developer on Shattered Heaven project, contributing to creation of game using Unity engine and C# programming language. During development, handled various technical aspects, optimizing game performance, and implementing key features to ensure smooth and engaging gaming experience.
- Developed and implemented game levels with in-game mechanics.
- Collaborated with artists and sound designers to create cohesive aesthetics across all aspects of game projects.

2024-12 -Current

Tech React E-commerce

Personal Project, R (Remote)

- Improved App functionality using JSX, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript and React.
- Creation of a tech e-commerce via DummyJSON API
- Enhanced website user experience by implementing responsive Tailwind CSS design.

2024-05 -2024-05

Cocktail React App

Personal Project, Remote

- Improved App functionality by redesigning, updating, and implementing JSX, CSS, JavaScript and React.
- The application is built to be fully responsive.
- API integration to have a large amount of cocktails available.

2024-04 -2024-07

E-Commerce, Front-end Developer

Personal Project, Remote

- Improved website functionality by redesigning, updating, and implementing HTML 5, CSS, and JavaScript codes.
- Researched topics to create accurate and engaging content.
- Enhanced website user experience by implementing responsive design and intuitive navigation.

2024-10 -2024-10

Portfolio, Front-End Web Developer

Holiday Home, Front-end Developer

Personal Project, Remote

- My personal portfolio website showcases skills and projects in web/game development and mechanics. Designed the site to reflect my personal style, featuring a clean layout and intuitive navigation. It includes detailed sections on my work, technical skills, and contact information.
- This website was created with HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript.

2024-01 -2024-02

Challenge Project, Remote

- Holiday home website was created to promote a beautiful vacation home. It provides visitors with detailed information about accommodations, services, and local attractions. With a user-friendly interface and captivating photographs, the site aims to deliver an engaging experience for potential guests.
- Improved website user experience by redesigning interface and optimizing navigation.
- This website was created with HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript.

2017-01 -Current

CNC Programmer

Toscoter S.P.A., Lucca, Italy

Programmed work paths for lathes.

• Reviewed CNC designs for pre-production errors, eliminating

Italian	
	Bilingual or Proficient (C2)
English	

Upper intermediate (B2) 2017-01 -

design flaws to reduce raw material waste.

- Inspected finished products to verify compliance with production tolerances.
 - Improved CNC program efficiency by optimizing tool paths and reducing cycle times.

2017-01 - Quality Control Inspector Current

Toscotec S.P.A., Lucca, Italy

- Inspected incoming and outgoing materials for accuracy and quality.
- Communicated with production team members about quality issues.
- Completed precise measurements using special tools.

Education

2011-09 -2016-07

High School Diploma

I.T.I.S Enrico Fermi, Mechanical Course - Lucca, Italy

Certifications

2021-06

Certified game designer, Gamera Interactive - 2022

Hobbies and Sports

A highly active individual with a passion for outdoor adventures and fitness. Regularly enjoys mountain hiking, skiing, swimming, and gym workouts, along with a variety of other sports. Always seeking new challenges and experiences, combining physical endurance with a love for nature and well-being.